<DATASET>

    <ROW ID="1">
        <SCHEME>New Swarnima Scheme For Women</SCHEME>
        <DESC>A term loan scheme by the Ministry of Social Justice and Empowerment for women entrepreneurs from backward classes to obtain a loan of up to ₹2,00,000/- @ 5% per annum, thereby providing them social and financial security. The scheme is introduced by National Backward Classes Finance and Development Corporation (NBCFDC) and implemented by State Channelising Agencies (SCAs) which act as the nodal agency.</DESC>
    </ROW>

    <ROW ID="2">
        <SCHEME>Pradhan Mantri Kaushal Vikas Yojana - Short Term Training</SCHEME>
        <DESC>STT component imparted at PMKVY Training Centres (TC) is expected to benefit candidates of Indian nationality who are either school/college dropouts or unemployed. Apart from providing training according to the National Skills Qualification Framework (NSQF), TCs also impart training in soft skills, entrepreneurship, financial and digital literacy. Upon successful completion of assessment, candidates are provided placement assistance by training providers.</DESC>
    </ROW>

    <ROW ID="3">
        <SCHEME> Pradhan Mantri Formalisation Of Micro Food Processing Enterprises</SCHEME>
        <DESC>Scheme designed to address the challenges faced by the micro-enterprises and to tap the potential of groups and cooperatives in supporting the upgradation and formalization of these enterprises.</DESC>
    </ROW>

    <ROW ID="4">
        <SCHEME> Direct Loans For Business Enterprise</SCHEME>
        <DESC>The main objective of this scheme is to provide financial assistance in the form of loans to persons belonging to the State's Religious Minority Communities so as to help them to start their businesses or expand their existing ones.</DESC>
    </ROW>

    <ROW ID="5">
        <SCHEME>Mukhyamantri Yuva Swarojgar Yojana</SCHEME>
        <DESC> This scheme has been started by the state government to make the youth of Chhattisgarh self-employed and make them economically independent and self-reliant. To provide overall assistance like financial assistance, guarantee, training, and follow-up to the youth of the state in setting up industry service and business as self-employment, so that according to their ability and working capacity, they can easily help and get success in setting up their own enterprises. </DESC>
    </ROW>

    <ROW ID="6">
        <SCHEME>Financial Assistance To Disabled For Self Employment</SCHEME>
        <DESC>The objective of this scheme is to facilitate the self-employment of unemployed disabled persons. Under this scheme, financial assistance is provided to persons with disabilities for self-employment, small-scale business, and agro-based project. </DESC>
    </ROW>

    <ROW ID="7">
        <SCHEME>Udyogini Scheme</SCHEME>
        <DESC> Udyogini is an innovative scheme sanctioned by the Government of Karnataka to assist women in gaining self-reliance and economic independence through self-employment, mainly through trade and the service sector.</DESC>
    </ROW>

    <ROW ID="8">
        <SCHEME>National Handicrafts Development Programme: Infrastructure And Technology Support: EMPORIA</SCHEME>
        <DESC>The scheme "Infrastructure and Technology Support: EMPORIA" is a Component/Sub-Scheme under the Umbrella Scheme "National Handicrafts Development Programme". Under this component, assistance would be provided for the setting up of emporia. These would be set up in commercially viable locations in the implementing agencies' own/rented buildings. The basic objective of the component is to provide a marketing platform to the Local Handicrafts Artisans in their respective area through the outlet and emporia.</DESC>
    </ROW>

    <ROW ID="9">
        <SCHEME>Rise Together</SCHEME>
        <DESC> The programme shall be focused on introducing and developing community oriented entrepreneurship in JandK by providing strategic and financial assistance to dynamic and motivated youth. The programme envisions promoting community based entrepreneurship optimally to generate jobs, income and promote spirit of social service among new-age young entrepreneurs of Jammu and Kashmir</DESC>
    </ROW>

    <ROW ID="10">
        <SCHEME>Skilled Youth Startup Scheme</SCHEME>
        <DESC>  The "Skilled Youth Start-Up Scheme (SYSS)" was launched with effect on 15th August 2020 by the Commerce and Industries Department of the Government of Sikkim, with the vision to reduce unemployment and create adequate self-employment opportunities in the long run. SYSS is intended to generate equitable entrepreneurial opportunities in rural as well as urban areas of Sikkim, particularly among the educated unemployed youth to become self-employed by setting up Manufacturing / Service / Business / Co-Operative / Agriculture and Allied Activities by availing loans (category wise) with back ended subsidy assistance from the State Government @ 50% for Below Poverty Line (BPL) and @ 35% for rest on financially viable/ bankable Projects cost. </DESC>
    </ROW>

</DATASET>